#### Contact

9884794231 (Fax) sasidharan.hr@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sasidharan-murugesan-aa6679a3 (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Talent Management
MS Excel Pivot Tables
Microsoft Excel

# Languages

English (Full Professional)

Tamil (Native or Bilingual)

Malayalam (Professional Working)

# Sasidharan Murugesan

Talent Acquisition Lead at Technicolor

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

# Summary

Experienced Talent Acquisition Lead with a demonstrated history of working in the motion pictures and film industry. Skilled in Microsoft Word, Management, Interviewing, MICROS, and Recruiting. Strong human resources professional with a Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.) focused in HR & Marketing from Rajalakshmi Engineering College.

# Experience

Technicolor Creative Studios 2 years 8 months

Talent Acquisition Lead July 2022 - Present (1 year 3 months) Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Talent Acquisition Manager February 2021 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

The Focus comprises a team of experts in recruitment, marketing and learning & development who work towards meeting the demands of Technicolor's brands across visual effects, advertising, creative experience and animation. As a central hub The Focus provides job opportunities, career guidance, industry insights, events, and helpful learning materials to help professionals progress in their career.

#### **RPM VFX STUDIOS**

Senior Human Resources Manager July 2019 - April 2020 (10 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Developing, building and maintaining a strategic human resources function that supports Visai's business strategy. Align policy and programs with the organization's strategic plan, mission, values and culture. Employee relations, diversity and inclusion, benefits, performance management, compensation,

compliance, professional development, change planning and facilitation, team coaching and organization development.

#### MIST VFX

Human Resources Manager November 2017 - July 2019 (1 year 9 months)

Chennai & Kochi, India. South Region

- Recruitment
- Work Force Management
- Time & Attendance Management
- 360 Feedback Performance Management Solution
- Employee Performance Management & Engagement activities
- Employee Self Service
- Payroll Management Leave Management
- Loan Management
- · Performance Management
- Project Tracking & Employee Job Costing

# Cognizant Technology Solutions

Senior Executive HR

August 2011 - August 2017 (6 years 1 month)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Chennai Area, India

Recruitment & On-boarding:

- >Lead PAN India Campus On-boarding and Supported for Campus Hiring.
- >Supported lateral hiring for IT & BPO.
- >Handles New hire Inductions for Campus hires and Co-ordinate induction for Leadership hires.
- >Lead the digitization of manual files for Chennai.
- >Automated manual On-boarding to Electronic process, with ZERO manual forms on Day 1.
- >SPOC for New hire file Audit and Co-ordinate SOX audits.

#### Verifications:

- >Responsible for Chennai location New hire verification for both IT & BPO.
- >Lead 30+ client account specific verification who moves internally.
- >Laying down process and documents like SOP for new client accounts and M&A.
- >Automated BGV process and internal tool for verification.

>SPOC for all Client Audits.

### Learning & Development:

- >Handled the ELT training in Academy.
- >Specialist in adhering the training duration and release of the associates ON time to Projects.
- >Track their performances and ensure 100% release with SLA.
- >Handles employee grievances on day to day basis.
- >Location SPOC for an external training center.
- >Handles the off-boarding of the associates while in Academy.
- >Handles Reporting and Academy Dashboard for PAN India.

### Start-Up L&D Project (Early Engagement):

- >Heads the Operations Learning Platform designed for training freshers online.
- >Enrollment, Calendar schedule for different events like contests, webinars, Leadership connects etc.,
- >Leads Support Management team to handle queries thru tickets, Q&A forum & Facebook.
- >Publish Ranking based on performance and co-ordinate with Campus HR for on-boarding based on Ranks.
- >Work on feedback and get it developed & implemented in platform

# Education

Rajalakshmi Engineering College

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), HR & Marketing · (2009 - 2011)